翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
Hello everybody i don't often make videos on Windows builds but it's one of those times when I'm just disappointed
大家好，我不常做关于Windows构建的视频，但这次真是让我失望透顶的时候了
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
The new Windows 11 beta build changes the blue screen of death to show even less information
Windows 11新测试版更新进一步简化蓝屏死机显示信息
and then on top of that removes the essential oobe\bypassNRO script
除此之外，还移除了关键的oobe\bypassNRO脚本
See it's no longer found
看到了吗，它不见了
For those of you who aren't familiar the oobe\bypassNRO script
对于那些不熟悉oobe\bypassNRO脚本的人来说
helped you bypass the network requirements inside the out-of-box experience
这个会帮你在开箱体验中绕过网络要求
as you can see the script makes the computer reboot
正如你所见，这个脚本会导致电脑重启
and pass the reboot it's not going to ask you to connect to the internet
重启后不会要求你连接互联网
So that you can create a local account
这样你就可以创建本地账户了
and avoid the forced Microsoft account requirement
避免强制要求使用微软账户
it's the fallback copy here but doesn't really matter
这是备用方案，不过无关紧要了
so technically if you're an ordinary grandma that knows nothing about Windows
所以严格来说，如果你是个对Windows一窍不通的普通老奶奶
or even slightly more technology proficient user that knows
甚至是稍微懂点技术的用户都知道
how to search things online you can no longer install Windows without connecting to the internet
如何在线搜索东西，你现在不连接互联网就无法安装Windows
and connecting it with the godforsaken Microsoft account
还要把它和那个该死的微软账户关联起来
it looks like I've lost my internet connection and I cannot continue
看起来我的网络连接断了，我无法继续
Let's see what our blog has to say about these two drastic design changes
来看看我们的博客对这两项重大设计变更有何见解
here's the official Microsoft blog post on the newest beta build we're talking about
这是我们讨论的最新测试版官方Microsoft博客文章
here they list the entire change log but we're more particularly interested in
这里列出了完整的变更日志，但我们更特别感兴趣的是
how they describe the change of the bug check and the removal of the bypass NRO
他们如何描述漏洞检查的变更及绕过NRO机制的移除
so let's go ahead and read that out loud
那么我们就大声读出来吧
we're previewing a new more streamlined UI for unexpected restarts
我们正在预览一个针对意外重启设计的更简洁的新用户界面
which better aligns with Windows 11 design principles
更符合Windows 11的设计原则
and supports our goal of getting users back into productivity as fast as possible
并支持我们让用户尽快恢复高效工作的目标
look how they sugarcoat it
看看他们是怎么粉饰的
we've simplified your experience while preserving the technical information on the screen
我们在简化您体验的同时，保留了屏幕上的技术信息
as a reminder for Windows Insiders this appears as a green screen
为了提醒Windows Insider用户，这会显示为绿屏
No nothing new here this is beginning to roll out
这里没什么新消息。这正开始向
Windows Insiders on Windows 11 version
Windows 11版本的Windows Insiders推出
24H2 and higher in the beta dev and canary channels
Beta dev 和 canary 通道中的24H2及更高版本
Here's how that looks they stripped the bug check of the said smiley and the QR code
这就是他们如何移除了所说的笑脸和二维码的错误检查
and the rest seems pretty much the same I got to say I actually hate the word streamlined
其余的看起来几乎没什么差别，我得说我真的很讨厌 “流水线” 这个词
it's basically become a euphemism for stripping the features away from the user
这基本上成了剥夺用户功能的委婉说法
I mean I wouldconsider the QR code a feature of sorts
我的意思是，我认为二维码也算是一种特色功能
because I mean it looked more friendly to the user
因为我觉得这对用户看起来更友好
this looks kind of threatening it has a threatening aura if you know what I mean
这看起来有点威胁性，它散发着一种威胁的气场，如果你明白我的意思的话
not everything needs to be streamlined that's my point especially
不是所有事情都需要流水线化，这正是我的观点所在
not the screen that shows you important debug information
不是显示重要调试信息的那个屏幕
pretty disappointing Microsoft another horrible pointless change
相当令人失望，微软又一次做出了毫无意义的糟糕改动
well we have no control over that
好吧，我们对那件事无能为力
but what's happening to Windows lately is absolute cinema
但Windows最近的动态简直像在上演大片
I have nothing else to say about it
关于这件事，我无话可说了
I'll read the announcement of the next change directly from the blog as well
我也会直接从博客上宣读下一个变更的公告
See what they haveto say about the bypassNRO script
看看他们对绕过NRO脚本有什么看法
we're removing the bypassnro.cmd script from the build to enhance
我们将从构建中移除bypassnro.cmd脚本以增强
security and user experience of Windows 11
Windows 11的安全性与用户体验
this change ensures that all users exit setup with an internet connectivity
这一更改确保所有用户在完成设置时具备互联网连接
and a Microsoft account you lovely saints thank you for enhancing my security
还有微软账户，你们这些可爱的圣人，感谢你们提升了我的安全性
aka forcing me to connect my computer to the internet
也就是逼我把电脑连上网
and enhancing my user experience aka forcing me to log into the Microsoft account
以及提升我的用户体验，也就是强迫我登录微软账户
I cannot express my frustration with the gaslighting that's happening in this blog post
我无法表达对这篇博文中出现的煤气灯效应感到的沮丧
I don't want a Microsoft account and what if that's an offline computer that's only connected to the local area network
我不想使用微软账户，如果那是一台仅连接到局域网的离线电脑怎么办
because this is my computer
因为这是我的电脑
and it's security and user experience is my concern and none of your business
它的安全性和用户体验是我关心的事，与你无关
get the hell off my face with this stupid forced Microsoft account BS
带着你这强制登录微软账户的废话滚出我的视线
also do you hear that these dogs are out of control
你有没有听说这些狗已经失控了
so I couldn't get the new blue screen to show up no matter which branch I downloaded the build from
无论我从哪个分支下载构建版本，都没法让新的蓝屏界面显示出来
but I don't think it's anything special that can't be shown in a single frame
但我并不觉得这有什么特别之处，特别到无法用一帧画面来展现
just want to let you know I couldn't get it to work
只是想告诉你我没能搞定它
for some reason i've been trying for like the past two days
不知为何，我这两天一直在尝试
in theory the new bug check should be available in the
理论上新的错误检查应该会在
beta dev and canary builds with a feature ID 50070238
具有功能ID 50070238的Beta dev和 canary 版本
and ideally you should be able
理想情况下,你应该能够
to turn it on using Vive tool
使用Vive工具来开启它
My attempts failed and the feature flag reset leaving me with the old bug check
我的尝试失败了，功能标志被重置，让我又回到了旧的错误检查状态
I mean we have the screenshots
我是说我们有截图
Imagine though it's an early April Fool's joke or something and that's the reason
想象一下，这或许是四月初的一个愚人节玩笑之类的，所以才是这个原因
I can't reproduce that right now
我现在无法复现那个问题
that'd be super funny
那会超级搞笑
anyway that's a slightly more simplified version of the current bug check without a smiley
总之，这是当前错误检查的一个稍微简化的版本，没有笑脸
rest in peace
安息 ╯︿╰
and it's also going to be black in production builds
并且在生产版本中它也会是黑色的
yet again meaning BSOD yet again stands for the black screen of death instead of blue screen of death
又一次意味着BSOD，这里的yet again代表黑屏死机而非蓝屏死机
whatever man can't wait to see them reverted again a couple builds later
随便吧，反正等不及要看它们在几个版本后又被改回来的样子
as for the bypass and the rose script
至于跳过脚本
it was a script after all so let's go ahead and examine the contents of it
这毕竟是个脚本，那么我们就来看看它的内容吧
to learn what exactly it used to do on the older builds
了解它在旧版本中具体用来做什么
looks like nothing much
看起来也没有多少东西
So first of all it silences the output of the batch script using the at echo off macro
首先，它通过使用echo off宏来静默批处理脚本的输出
then it adds a registry value called BypassNRO with a type registry dword
然后它会添加一个名为BypassNRO的注册表值，类型为REG_DWORD
and sets it to one
并且设为1
inside the OOBE key
路径是在oobe（看视频不是看这里啦）  (/▽＼)
then it restarts the computer pretty simple
然后它会重启电脑，非常简单
that's all it does let's see if it works on the newer version of Windows
这就是它的全部功能，我们来看看它在较新版本的Windows上是否能用
okay we're back on the newest version of Windows 11
好的，我们回到了最新版的Windows 11
let's verify that by showing the version
让我们通过显示版本来验证这一点
right here 26120
就在这 26120
script no longer works it just doesn't exist
脚本不再有效，它根本不存在了
let's go ahead and verify there's no internet connection present
让我们继续验证当前没有互联网连接
by skimming through the first part of the oobe
浏览oobe的第一部分
let's connect you to a network and there is no option to skip the network check
让我们为您连接到网络，且无法跳过网络检查
now let's open the registry editor then find the key
现在让我们打开注册表编辑器，然后找到该键值
let's create a new dword value called bypassNRO
让我们创建一个名为bypassNRO的新DWORD值
set it to one very nice
把它设为1，好的
and then restart we have basically manually reproduced the script
然后重启，我们基本上已经手动复制了这个脚本
have they turned it off in the out of box experience let's find out
他们在开箱体验中关掉了吗？让我们一探究竟
oh wow you still have the button huge
哇哦，你的按钮居然还这么大
so the only thing they did was to remove the BypassNRO script
所以他们唯一做的就是移除了BypassNRO脚本
but the registry setting is still present
但注册表设置仍然存在
which is actually great great news
这是个天大的好消息
now it's going to take them another six months to remove the registry value from the oobe
现在他们还需要六个月才能从OOBE中移除注册表值
and yeah you can still bypass the network requirements
是的，你仍然可以绕过网络要求
even though the script is gone
尽管脚本已不复存在
got to turn all this garbage off
得把这些垃圾都关掉
before proceeding all right
在进行之前，好的
and we're in
我们进来了
beautiful
太美
another trick you guys can employ to bypass the network requirements
你们可以用来绕过网络要求的另一个技巧
is using the protocol commands basically the out of box experience application
是使用协议命令，基本上是开箱即用的体验应用
provides us a protocol
提供了一个协议
and there are a couple commands they have implemented
他们已经实现了几个命令
and some of them remain from Windows 10
其中一些仍保留自Windows 10
I showed off many of these commands in a video from like a year ago
大约一年前的一个视频里我就展示过很多这些命令
experimenting on the out of box experience application
在开箱即用体验应用上进行实验
that's also when I found there is a developer console in the in the oobe
也就是在那时我发现OOBE界面里有个开发者控制台
wait did they fix it wait it doesn't work anymore
等等，他们修好了吗？它又不能用了
used to be able to press control shift J and open up the developer console
过去可以按Ctrl+Shift+J打开开发者控制台
wow I think they removed it from production finally
哇，我觉得他们终于把它从生产环境中移除了
anyway the protocol this application provides is called ms-cxh
无论如何，这个应用程序提供的协议称为ms-cxh
and you can run commands using start
你可以使用start来运行命令（看视频操作啦）  ~(￣▽￣)~*
and then input your command and one of those commands is local only
然后输入你的命令，其中有一个命令仅限本地使用
whenever you run that it opens a dialogue box
每次运行它都会弹出一个对话框
to create a user for this computer
为此计算机创建用户
we can
我们可以
name our user and add a password
命名账户和设置密码
the security questions are also on the same page which which is pretty nice
安全问题也在同一页面上，这相当不错
I should say
我应该说
that's um that's also a piece of a fallback oobe
这个也是备用的OOBE的一部分
you can break this application to run that as well
你可以破坏这个应用程序来运行它
let's go ahead and click next
我们继续点击下一步
and it just basically skips the entire out of box experience and we're in
它基本上直接跳过了整个开箱体验，我们就直接进入了
super super nice but
超级超级棒但是
the only downside to that is you'll be faced with
唯一的缺点是你将面临
a second chance obby as they call it SC oobe
第二个要求页面
which will pest you to choose privacy settings and what not
这会让你烦恼地去选择隐私设置之类的
and you just accept it once and you move on with your day
你就接受一次然后继续过你的日子
anyway I hope you enjoyed the video i certainly am not enjoying Microsoft
无论如何，希望你喜欢这个视频，反正我是一点都不享受微软的体验
going down the rogue path
走上堕落之路
preparing the users for a forced Microsoft account integration
为用户强制整合Microsoft账户做准备
luckily this is not possible to achieve with the current Windows architecture
幸运的是，以目前的Windows架构无法实现这一点
the local users are pretty much baked into the system
本地用户几乎已深植于系统之中
and I don't see how they're going to police this
我看不出他们打算如何监管这件事
but the trend is quite obvious i'm a big fan of Windows personally
但趋势相当明显，我个人是Windows的忠实粉丝
but damn Linux for personal use is looking real hot right now
但说真的，Linux现在对个人用户来说简直香到不行
原标题：Windows 11 Never Stops Disappointing (And Fixing It) 原作者：Enderman
原视频上传日期：2025年4月1日
that's it thanks for watching take care
就这样，感谢观看，生活愉快
在 Youtube 上关注
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
向所有字幕制作及相关人员道一声辛苦了 (*ˊᗜˋ*)/ᵗᑋᵃᐢᵏ ᵞᵒᵘ*
感谢字幕组的默默耕耘，你们的每一行字都能让更多人能够跨越语言障碍，享受精彩的内容
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！